Finding Aid for the Roy E. Simpson Papers LSC.0842
UCLA Library Special Collections
Roy E. Simpson papers
1945-1958
UCLA Library Special Collections
Simpson, Roy E.
LSC.0842
30 oversize boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Roy E. Simpson.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942337853606533
Biographical / Historical
Simpson was born on March 15, 1893 in Santa Rosa, California; attended Heald's Business College in San Francisco, Armstrong College in Berkeley, and UC Berkeley; AB, Pomona College, and MA, Claremont College, 1931; taught at Anderson Union High School, 1915-17, serving as principal there, 1919-27; principal of Emerson Junior High School in Pomona and Pomona Evening High School; served as district superintendent of Gilroy Union High School District and Gilroy Elementary School District (1933-37), city superintendent of schools at Santa Cruz (1937-39), and district superintendent of the South Pasadena-San Marino Union High School District and South Pasadena Elementary School District (1939-45); served as president of the Association of California Public School Superintendents (1944); served as head of the public school system of California, 1945-63; served as president of the national Council of Chief State School Officers (1953-54).
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of scrapbooks containing clippings from various California newspapers concerning public education in the state, and documenting the administration of Roy E. Simpson as state superintendent of instruction.
Simpson, Roy E.
- 1945, 1946, 1947 (Box 1)
- 1947, 1948 (Box 2)
- 1948 (Box 3)
- 1949 (Box 5)
- 1950 (Box 6)
- 1950 (Box 7)
- 1951, 1952 (Box 8)
- 1952 (Box 9)
- 1952 (Box 10)
- 1952 (Box 11)
- 1953 (Box 12)
- 1953 (Box 13)
- 1953 (Box 14)
- 1954 (Box 15)
- 1954 (Box 16)
- 1954 (Box 17)
- 1954, 1955 (Box 18)
- 1955 (Box 19)
- 1955 (Box 20)
- 1955 (Box 21)
- 1956 (Box 22)
- 1956 (Box 23)
- 1956 (Box 24)
- 1957 (Box 25)
- 1957 (Box 26)
- 1957 (Box 27)
- 1957 (Box 28)
- 1958; Southern California Citizens' School Committee (Box 29)
- 1958 (Box 30)